(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-14T01:04:22.859623",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
くだらない潔癖で籠城
Holed up in trivial fastidiousness,
お利口すぎて欠伸が出ちゃう
Being too good-mannered just makes me yawn.
ねぇ、見て？
Hey, look?
目の前のドアの鍵は握ってるでしょ？
You're holding the key to the door right in front of you, right?
飲み込まれないで ほら
Don't get swallowed up, come on.
お前の欲しいものは何だ
What is it that you want?
掴んでいけよ 信じた道で
Seize it along the path you believed in.
ゲームがいつでも勝者の手の上でも
Even if the game is always in the winner's hands,
貫いていくの
I'll push right through it.
甘い囁きは 銀と黒
Sweet whispers in silver and black,
とっくに蠅が集まって崩壊
Flies have long since gathered and caused a collapse.
簡単な道はどうやら無い
There's seemingly no easy way out.
冗談みたい コントロールも効かない
Like a joke, even control fails us.
その癖 毎秒 選択迫られ
Yet every second we're forced to choose,
嫌になるでしょ？
Aren't you sick of it?
たった一つでいい 決めろ
Just one is enough, make your choice.
お前の譲れないものは何だ
What is the one thing you cannot yield?
認めてやれよ 歪な心
Acknowledge your distorted heart.
今だけは一歩も引けないな
Not a single step back, at least for now.
目眩は止められない
I can't stop the dizziness...
早く々々された見舞いなんてない
There's no such thing as rushed pity...
ないものねだりさどうしようもないくらい
Wanting what you don't have, to a hopeless degree.
遠い街角少し不気味になって
A distant street corner grows slightly eerie,
僕らには僕らの戦いがきっとあるだろう
Surely we have our own battles to fight.
ぶち抜いて
Blast right through it!
“さよなら”は引き止めてって
"Goodbye" means "please hold me back,"
“大丈夫”はだいじょばなくて
"I'm fine" means "I'm not okay at all,"
“もういい”は全然良くなくて
"I've had enough" means "things are far from good,"
そのままの私でいて言って
Telling me to just stay as I am.
ノイズ 作詞・作曲：ミオヤマザキ
[Noise - Lyrics & Music: Mio Yamazaki]
本当をもっともっとあなたの事を知りたいよって一緒にいたいよって
I want to know more and more about you, I want to be together with you,
伝えたら離れてしまいそうで
But if I tell you, it feels like we'll drift apart,
だから守る事幸せとした
So I chose to find happiness in protecting you.
ねぇ ちゃんと目見て話したらきっと伝わるような気がしてるんだよ
Hey, if I look you in the eye and talk, I feel like it'll surely get across.
「面倒くさい」「怖い」「嫌い」でも「好き」をんなじなら
"Boring," "Scary," "I hate you," but also "I love you"—if they're all the same,
キレイだと思ってた場所見つけた気になっていただけだ
I was just under the illusion I had found a place I thought was beautiful.
逃げるヤツが幸せになる世界ならば幸せなんて
If this is a world where those who run away find happiness,
要らない要らないもう要らない
Then I don't need happiness anymore, no, I don't need it at all.
いつだって一人で抱えるあなた　ただ見守るしか出来ない私
You always bear everything alone; I'm someone who can only watch over you.
力になりたいと思うのに　どうすればいいのか分からない
Even though I want to be of help, I don't know what I should do.
繰り返していく　忘れたれきっと誰かがまた傷つくから
It repeats over and over—if we forget, someone will surely get hurt again.
傷に傷を重ねたのは忘れる為？それとも……
Did we pile scar upon scar just to forget? Or is it...
“さよなら”は引き止めてって
"Goodbye" means "please hold me back,"
“大丈夫”はだいじょばなくて
"I'm fine" means "I'm not okay at all,"
“もういい”は全然良くなくて
"I've had enough" means "things are far from good,"
そのままの私じゃダメなら
If just staying as I am isn't good enough,
ヘタクソな生き方でしか生きられない私達はきっと一人では出来ないことも
Living clumsily is the only way we know how; surely things we couldn't do alone
二人でなら出来るようなそんな存在になりたかったな
We wanted to become a presence that could achieve them together.
言えない言えないもう言えない
I can't say it, I can't say it, I can't say it anymore.
Here 作詞：岩里祐穂 作曲：白戸佑輔
[Here - Lyrics: Iwaishi Yuho / Music: Shirato Yusuke]
たったひとつ たったひとつの たったひとり たったひとりの わたしはここ
The one and only, the one and only, all alone, all alone, I am here.
瓦礫の胸 息もできない 降り出す雨 眠るように 泣く
With my heart in shambles and unable to breathe, I cry as the falling rain slumbers.
この世界を生き抜くのならば どんな花を飾ればいいの? 信じたいくせに 信じられずに
If I'm to survive this world, what flowers should I adorn it with? Even though I want to believe, I cannot.
無力で無意味な自分が それでも心で泣いたんだ こっちへおいでと 声が聴こえる
A powerless and meaningless self, yet I cried with my heart. I hear a voice calling out, "Come here."
青い惑星に生まれて
Born on a blue planet,
違う道を歩いて
walking down different paths,
たどり着いたこの街
I ended up in this town.
光る粒が弾けた
Shining droplets burst open.
巡る夜にキミと出会い
Meeting you in the revolving night,
いつの間にか手を繋いで
holding hands before we knew it.
笑い声と弾む足で
With laughter and bouncing steps,
どこまでもし走れるミッドナイト
a midnight runaway to anywhere.
私はここ
I am right here.
いっそ素直になりたくない
If we could just be honest with ourselves,
いっそ分かり合えないなら
would we finally understand each other?
この世界を叩き抜くなら
If we're going to shake up this world,
どんな歌は歌えばいいの
what kind of song should I sing?
見つけたいなら 見つけ出すまで
I want to find it before it vanishes.
無力で無意味な自分が
Powerless and meaningless reasons,
それでも心で泣くんだ
even so, I screamed that I wanted them.
知ってる 苦薬に
Knowing the bitter medicine,
何度振りをして
I've had enough of these sleepless nights.
無色で無機質な光を
A colorless and emotionless light,
それでももう一度探した
still, I searched for it once more.
たった一つたった一つの
Just one by one, just one by one.
たった一人たった一人の
Just one person, just one person.
私はここ
I am right here.
君だけなの場所は
Just look at me now.
必ずある
Always and forever.
美しいこの星は
This beautiful star...
すべてを隠してるけど
I keep it all hidden away.
無力で無意味な自分が
Powerless and meaningless reasons,
それでも心で泣くんだ
even so, I'm crying inside.
こっちへおいでと
Come on, let's go out.
声が聞こえる
A voice echoes out.
無限で無謀な走したかが
Running endlessly and recklessly,
それでもどこかで待つから
even so, waiting somewhere ahead...
たった一つたった一つの
Just one by one, just one by one.
たった一人たった一人の
Just one person, just one person.
私はここ
I am right here.
リンリン ドンドン リンリン ドンドン
Ring-ring, boom-boom, ring-ring, boom-boom,
チャイムが響く
the chime echoes.
スカート、メイクOK。
Skirts and makeup ready.
立ち軽え 坂を登る
Standing lightly, climbing the slope.
放課後から始まる 君と僕のステージ
A stage for you and me starting after school.
「刺激欲しいよ...」って 叫んだ
I screamed, "Give me some stimulation!"
ピカピカな 宿題を 持っていたの いつも
Always carrying a bright homework assignment.
教科書の 落書きが「17's」
Doodles in the textbook say "17's".
気づいたら 一日が 終わっちゃった おやすみwww
Before I knew it, the day was over, good night lol.
ハッピー いっぱい ハッピー
Happy, so happy!
リンリン ドンドン リンリン ドン
Ring-ring, boom-boom, ring-ring, boom...
チャイムが響く
The chime echoes.
デニムに、スッピンOK。
Denim and no makeup, OK.
カーテン、遮光に変えた
The curtains changed to blackout.
満員電車 乗り込み 一人きりのステージ
Boarding the packed train, a stage for one.
「刺激足りない...」って 叫んだ
I screamed, "Not enough stimulation!"
あの頃へ 戻れない そんな事知ってる
I can't go back to those days, I know that.
飽きる ほど 悩んだら「17's」
I worried myself sick over it, "17's".
懐かしい あの 場所 へ いつものメンバーで
To those nostalgic places with the usual members.
ハッピー いっぱい ハッピー
Happy, so happy!
思い切って 飛び出せる この 瞬間 も「17's」「17's」
Deciding to leap out in that moment, "17's", "17's".
ずっとずっと 変わらずに 笑えればいいだね
If we can just keep smiling unchanged forever.
ハッピー いっぱい ハッピー
Happy, so happy!
一ト年しても私は
Even if a year passes, I'm still...
そうてきいで
so clumsy.
一人のオリジナル
A lone original,
ホロラジク思って
Thinking so wistfully.
増えてけない嬉しいな
It's more than I could ever ask for.
境界の線で切り分けて
Dividing the border with a blade,
こちら側の世界だ今日の僕の
On the other side of this world,
キングデムキネ電使くひする
The cowardly, naive me nods.
見つけちゃった悪みの口はいいから帰り道をこう換しよう
Let's exchange our ways home,
帰り道を交換しよう
Let's exchange our ways home.
私が希望になるののお別れは
The parting that would make me hopeful...
少し寂しいけれど
Was a bit lonely, but...
いつか目尻に作った傷もりんじに立ち向かった
The scars I made on my fingertips someday...
証だから
Were proof of that.
いつかハッピーエンドになるまで
Until that happy ending arrives,
世界を相手に戦うの
I'll keep fighting the whole world.
こんなロブな私をずっと
I will keep playing these pathetic...
愛してくれてありがとう
Melodies that cherish you.
一ト年しても私は
Even if a year passes, I'm still...
あなたの唯一無二の
Your one and only...
オリジナル誇らしく生きるよ
Original, living so wistfully.
然るべき場所に帰ろうさよならを告げたセブンティーン
Saying goodbye, stepping into seventeen.
街を切り裂くような排気音が
The exhaust sound tearing through the streets
足元で唸っている 猛スピードで進む
Roars at my feet as I advance at high speed.
街を切るように裂くような排気音が
Searching for the whereabouts of the taillights that vanished,
足元で唸っている
I drive straight ahead.
もうスピードで進む
At full speed,
消えたテールランプの在り処探して真っ直ぐに
Even if the streetlights are gone along the path,
闇をスクラップにする強さで
I'm searching for them.
ひた走る道路にはもう街灯さえもないけれど
The wimpy voice buried under the rubble
きっとヘッドライト一つあれば何も要らないな瓦礫の下に埋もれた弱虫の声は
Cannot be heard no matter how much I strain my ears.
いくら耳澄ませても聞こえやしないさ追いかけてくる後悔が視界を塞ぐ前に
Before the regret chasing after me blocks my sight,
追いついた未来の端っこで何度もあなたを救い出すよ
I will save you at the edge of the future.
不意に記憶がブレーキをかけた舌打ちの矛先は覗き込むミラーの向こう
That day, I forgot the revenge I swore.
自身の意気地なさに気づいている時間なんかないのに瓦礫の下から漏れた弱虫の声は
Even now, my trembling heart screams that name.
いくら耳塞いでも痛いほど響いてたあの日誓ったリベンジを忘れていたまるかと
You were laughing, acting like a hero.
震えた心が今もうるさいほどその名前を叫んでるヒーローぶって笑っていたあなたの両頬を拭うまで止まらない
I won't stop until I wipe both your cheeks.
ああそうさあの夜からあなたを迎えに来たんだ何回しくじろうとも
That's right, I came to welcome you from that night.
ヒーローぶって笑っていたあなたの絶望を抱き締めるまで負けない
No matter how many times I screwed up,
運命に殴られても痛くも痒くもないと道路を駆け抜けてく
I won't lose until I embrace your despair.
瓦礫の下に埋もれた声を掻き消しながら
Drowning out the voice buried under the rubble.
不意に記憶がブレーキをかけた
Memory applied the brakes,
舌打ちの矛先は
And the target of my clicking tongue
覗き込むミラーの向こう
Is beyond the mirror I peer into.
自身の意気地なさに気づいている
I realize my own cowardice,
時間なんかないのに
Though I have no time for that.
瓦礫の下から漏れた弱虫の声は
The wimpy voice leaking from beneath the rubble
いくら耳塞いでも痛いほど響いてた
Echoed painfully, no matter how I covered my ears.
あの時誓ったリベンジを忘れていたまるかと
I had forgotten the revenge I swore that day,
震えた心が今もうるさいほどその名前を叫んでる
And my trembling heart still screams that name.
ヒーローぶって笑っていた
You laughed like a hero,
あなたの両頬を拭うまで止まらない
And I won't stop until I wipe your tears.
あの夜からあなたを迎えに来たんだ
I came to greet you from that night.
何回しくじろうとも
No matter how many times I messed up,
ヒーローぶって笑っていたあなたの絶望を抱き締めるまで負けない
I won't lose until I embrace your despair.
運命に殴られても痛くも痒くもないと道路を駆け抜けてく瓦礫の下に埋もれた声を掻き消しながら
Drowning out the voice under the rubble.
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
明け無い夜に失いかけた声を上げて
Raising the voice I almost lost in the endless night
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
振返れない僕の心はどこへ行くの、あー
Where is my unreturnable heart heading, ah—
閉ざされた世界で
In this closed-off world,
何が不要不急かも分からなくなってしまう
I lose sight of what's non-essential and unnecessary.
血にまみれてるメッセージ
A message stained with blood,
隠された口元じゃ何にも言えないだろう
You can't say anything with your mouth hidden, can you?
満たされない日々に囚われたくもないな
I don't want to be trapped in unfulfilling days either.
心の底から崩れかけた声を掻き消しながら
Drowning out the voice collapsing from the bottom of my heart—
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
明けない夜に失いかけた声を上げて
Raising the voice I almost lost in the endless night,
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
振り返れない僕の心はどこへ行くの
Where is my unreturnable heart heading?
閉ざされたその中で
Inside that closed-off space,
何が不要不急かも分からなくなってしまう
I lose sight of what's non-essential and unnecessary.
千切れてるメッセージ
A torn-apart message,
隠された口元じゃ何にも言えないだろう
You can't say anything with your mouth hidden, can you?
満たされない日々に
In unfulfilling days,
囚われたくないな 心の底から
I don't want to be trapped. From the bottom of my heart,
崩れかけた声を掻き消しながら
Drowning out the voice that started collapsing—
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
1人の夜はこんな想いが溢れていく
Such thoughts overflow on a night when I'm alone.
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
余裕の negative 同じように苦しめられて
Tormented just the same by leisurely negativity,
いらないいらない宣言なんて何度繰り返せばいいの
How many times must I repeat useless declarations?
もう意味なんてないよな
There's no meaning left anymore, right?
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
1人の夜も乗り越えられたらいいのにな
I wish I could overcome nights alone as well.
真っ暗な街中を
Through the pitch-black streets,
憂いを帯びた顔でバラバラに立ち去っていく
Leaving in pieces with sorrowful faces.
簡単に作られた意図的なマニュアルに全て奪われている
Everything is stolen by hastily made, intentional manuals.
今の世界は先が見えずどこにも救いはなくって
The world today has no foreseeable future and no salvation anywhere,
また次の犠牲者が増えていくの
And yet another victim continues to grow.
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
聞こえる声を探し続けてたどり着いた
I kept searching for a voice I could hear and arrived here.
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
不安な medicine もっと近くで触れたいのに
I want to touch an unsettling medicine closer by,
泣けない逢えないシンデレラ まだ帰る時間じゃないのに
A Cinderella who can't cry or meet, even though it's not time to go home yet,
魔法が解けていくの
The magic is wearing off.
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
いつかは君と朝まで踊り明かしたいんだ
Someday, I want to dance through the morning with you.
当たり前じゃないんだろう だったら答え探して
It's not a given, is it? Then go find the answer.
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
あの日の僕は夢は叶うと思ったけど
That day, I thought my dreams would come true, but...
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
諦めたくないなんて言葉じゃ頼りなくて
Saying 'I don't want to give up' feels so unreliable.
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
1人の夜はこんな想いが溢れていく
Such thoughts overflow on a night when I'm alone.
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
余裕の negative 同じように苦しめられて
Tormented just the same by leisurely negativity,
いらないいらない宣言なんて何度繰り返せばいいの
How many times must I repeat useless declarations?
もう意味なんてないよな
There's no meaning left anymore, right?
I'm a mess, I'm a mess
どんな世界も君と歩いていけるのなら
If I can walk with you through any kind of world...
音沙汰ないから帰ったの
I came back because there was no word,
君しかいないと言ってよ
Tell me that I'm the only one for you,
揺らつきたいから愛したの
I loved you because I wanted to waver,
タリラ リラッタッタ ララ
Tarira rilattatta lara.
ハレンチ
[Harenchi]
何度も遥か遠く 穴をかいたの
Countless times, far in the distance, I dug a hole.
大人びてしまった私は 金色で遊んでいたの
Having grown up, I was playing in golden colors.
あっちもこっちも身体を任せてみても なにもかもないの
Even letting my body surrender to here and there, nothing is left at all.
騒がしいこの浮き心に 誰が気付くと言うの
Who would notice this restless, fickle heart of mine?
どうでもいいから泣いたの 乱れ心も抱いてよ
I cried because I didn't care anymore, hold my disordered heart too.
代わりに何か横してよ
Do something for me in return.
タリラ リラッタッタ ララ
Tarira rilattatta lara.
忘れた 何の感覚もないやいやいや
I forgot, I don't feel a thing anymore, yeah, yeah, yeah.
忘れた あなたを失ったから
I forgot, because I lost you.
go ahead and take me out イタイわ tokyo sound
Go ahead and take me out, it hurts, this Tokyo sound.
都会は大嫌い 怒りっぽくて冷たい
I hate the city, it's hot-tempered and cold.
忙しくて愛らしい 血色のない私はhigh
Busy and adorable, I'm high with no sign of life.
誰彼いるのに誰もいないわ
Though there's all sorts of people, there's no one here.
どこにどこにどこにあるのかしら
Where on earth could it possibly be?
感謝も愛も込められやしないわ
I can't put gratitude or love into anything.
何度も何度も何度も気にしてるわ
Countless times, countless times, I keep worrying over and over.
悪意に泣いた日から風が強い夜が明けて
Since the day I cried out of malice, the strong-winded night has cleared,
君の匂いが消えて一人になったらどうしよう
What should I do if your scent fades and I'm left all alone?
タリラ リラッタッタ ララ
Tarira rilattatta lara.
音沙汰ないから泣いたの
I cried because there was no word from you,
君しかいないから帰ったの
I came back because you're the only one for me,
愛されたいから愛したの
I loved you because I wanted to be loved,
タリラ リラッタッタ ララ
Tarira rilattatta lara.
忘れた 何の感覚もないやいやいや
I forgot, I don't feel a thing anymore, yeah, yeah, yeah.
忘れた あなたを失ったから
I forgot, because I lost you.
音沙汰ないから泣いたの
I cried because there was no word from you,
君しかいないから帰ったの
I came back because you're the only one for me,
愛されたいから愛したの
I loved you because I wanted to be loved,
タリラ リラッタッタ ララ
Tarira rilattatta lara.
忘れた 何の感覚もないやいやいや
I forgot, I don't feel a thing anymore, yeah, yeah, yeah.
忘れた あなたを失ったから
I forgot, because I lost you.
月明かり 柳が揺れる 私は路傍の石
Moonlight, the willows sway, I am a pebble by the roadside.
想い馳せる あなたの姿形を数えるように
As if counting the shape and form of you, on whom my thoughts race.
別れ行く意味があるなら せめて悲しまないで
If there's a reason for us parting ways, at the very least, don't be sad.
沈黙から離れた空へ 一筋の愛を込めて
Pouring a single stream of love into the sky freed from silence.
どんな夜だって 失い続けたって
No matter the night, no matter how much we kept losing,
共に生きてきたろ 瞬くように
We've lived together, like a flash of light.
何かを求めて月を見ていた
Searching for something, I was looking at the moon.
嵐に怯える私の前に現れたのがあなたでよかった
I'm so glad it was you who appeared before me, frightened by the storm.
まるで何もかもがなかったかのように
As if none of it had ever happened at all.
この火は消えたりしない きっと
This fire will surely never go out.
何かを求めて月を見ていた
Searching for something, I was looking at the moon.
哀しみに怯える私の前に
Before me, frightened by sorrow...
月明かり 柳が揺れる
Moonlight, the willows swaying,
わたしは路傍の碑
I'm just a pebble by the road.
想い馳せるあなたの姿
My mind races at the thought of you
羊を数えるように
As if I were counting sheep.
まるで 何にもかもがなかったかのように
As if none of this had ever happened,
この日は 消えたりしない
This day will never fade away,
きっと
Surely...
その窓を風が叩けば 僅かに開け放して
When the wind beats at the window, open it just a crack,
ただひとつ そう ただひとつ 語り得ぬ声で叫ぶ
And scream in an unspeakable voice, just one thing.
ただひとつ
Just one thing,
そう ただひとつ
Yes, just one thing...
語り得ぬ声でだけ
With an unspeakable voice.
生まれ変わったとして 想い出せなくたって
If I'm to be reborn, even if I can't remember,
見つけてみせるだろう あなたの姿
I'll find you, your figure.
全てを燃やして月を見ていた
I burned everything and looked at the moon.
誰かがそれを哀れむとしても
Even if someone would pity me for it,
あなたがいれば幸せだったんだ
I was happy as long as you were with me.
およそ正しくなどなかったとしても 消えたりしない
Even if it wasn't entirely right, it will never fade.
消えたりしない
It will never fade.
名前を呼んで もう一度だけ
Call my name just one more time,
優しく包むその柔い声で
With your soft voice that gently wraps me.
月を頼りに掴んだ枝が あなただった
The branch I grasped following the moon was you.
何か求めて月を見ていた
I was looking up at the moon, searching for something,
嵐に怯えるわたしの前に現れたのがあなたでよかった
When I was frightened by the storm, I'm glad it was you who appeared before me.
まるで何もかもがなかったかのように
As if none of this had ever happened,
この日は 消えたりしない きっと
This day will never fade away, surely.
消えたりしない きっと
It will never fade away, surely.
私じゃダメですか
Am I not good enough for you?
誰よりもあなたを
Better than anyone else...
わかってるのは わかってるのは
I understand you, I know you,
きっと私だけ
I'm the only one who knows.
私じゃダメですか
Am I not good enough for you?
心は奪えない
I can't steal your heart.
わかってるのは わかってるのは
I know that, I know it, but
きっと私だけ
I'm always empty-headed.
ダーリン 全部あなたにあげる
Darling, I'll give you everything,
お気持ちはなんと愛で頂戴
My feelings are just love, please accept them.
ダーリン いつか認めておくれ
Darling, please acknowledge me someday.
その日が来るのを待っているわ ダーリン
I'm waiting for that day to come, darling.
一人じゃ意味がない
Being alone is meaningless,
言葉は生まれない
Words aren't born.
わかってるのは わかってるのは
I know that, I know it, but
にずっとそ知らぬふり
You always act indifferent.
ふたりじゃいられない
We can't be together,
心は触れない
Our hearts can't touch.
わかってるのは わかってるのはにずっと恥じしれず
I know that, but I'm always shameless.
私じゃダメですか ダーリン
Am I not good enough for you, darling?
ダーリン 全部あなたにあげる
Darling, I'll give you everything,
お遊び夢中でなんてロンリー
I'm crazy in love, what a mess,
ダーリン いっそ忘れておくれ
Darling, please forget me.
ダーリン いつか忘れておくれ
Darling, someday forget me,
終わりが来るのをお待たせしているわ
I'm keeping you waiting for the end to come.
ダーリン 全部あなたにあげる
Darling, I'll give it all to you,
お気持ちはちゃんと相手頂戴
so show me your true feelings in return.
ダーリン いつか認めておくれ
Darling, someday acknowledge me,
その日が来るのを待っているわ
I'm waiting for that day to come.
ラストチャンスに飢えたつま先が
My toes, starved for a last chance,
踊り出すまま駆けたこの夜空
ran across this night sky just as they started dancing.
並みのスタンスじゃ潤わない
An ordinary stance won't satisfy me,
星は宝石の憧れ
stars are the yearning of jewels.
浮かぶ涙と汗は血の名残り
Floating tears and sweat are the remnants of blood,
目の中でしか泳げなきゃ芝居
a performance if you can only swim within your eyes,
だけどステージが逃がさない
but the stage won't let you escape.
いついつまでも憧れ 焦がれているよ
Always, always longing, burning with desire.
I've never seen such a liar
生まれつきたっての底なし
Bottomless from birth,
This lie is love And this lie is a gift to the world
誰と生きたか思い出して
Remember who you lived with,
わたしが命を賭けるから
because I'm staking my life.
あなたは時間をくれたのでしょう?
You gave me time, didn't you?
あらゆる望みの総てを叶えたら ああ果せたら
If I fulfill all desires, ah, if I accomplish it,
あなたに会いたい 星に願いをかけて
I want to see you, making a wish upon a star.
戻れないなら大切にするの? 始めないなら高を括るよ
Is it precious because you can't go back? If you don't start, you'll underestimate it.
楽になる日はまず来ない 日々の中に集まる悲しい光
The day you get relief will never come, sad light gathering in days.
生まれつきだってば底なし
Bottomless from birth,
This lie is love And this lie is a gift to the world
誰を生きたか忘れちゃった!
I forgot who I lived as!
あなたに命が戻るなら わたしはどうなろうと構わないのに
If life returns to you, I don't care what happens to me,
どうやら総ては叶わない
though it seems not everything will come true.
叶わないならばあなたになりたい
If it won't come true, I want to become you.
星は砕き光る わたしが命を賭けるから
The stars shatter and shine, because I'm staking my life.
あなたは時間をくれたのでしょう?
You gave me time, didn't you?
あらゆる望みの総てを叶えたら ああ果せたら
If I fulfill all desires, ah, if I accomplish it,
あなたに会いたい
I want to see you.
あなたに命が戻るなら
If life returns to you,
届くなら
if it reaches you,
わたしはどうなろうと構わないのに
I don't care what happens to me,
どうやら総ては叶わない
though it seems not everything will come true.
叶わないならばあなたになりたい
If it won't come true, I want to become you.
星は砕き光る
The stars shatter and shine,
わたしが命を賭けるから
because I'm staking my life.
あなたは時間をくれたのでしょう?
You gave me time, didn't you?
あらゆる望みの総てを叶えたら
If I fulfill all desires,
ああ果せたら
ah, if I accomplish it,
あなたに会いたい 星に願いをかけて
I want to see you, making a wish upon a star.
さあ星の子たちよ よくお眠りなさい
Now, children of the stars, sleep well.
輝きは鈍らない あなたたちならば
Your brilliance will never dull, if it's you.
さあ星の子たちよ よく狙いなさい
Now, children of the stars, aim well.
またたきは許さない あなたたちならば
I won't forgive a single blink, if it's you.
全曲歌わせていただいたので、
Since I've performed all the songs,
こうしてねJ-POPの楽曲を
singing so many J-POP songs like this
たくさん歌うのは初めてなんじゃないかなと思います。はい。
might actually be a first for me. Yeah.
そしてね、いっぱいいろんな曲を聞いてもらいたかったので、MCもちょっと少なめにしてみました。
And since I wanted you to hear lots of different songs, I kept the MC a bit short.
うぇーい！え、よかった？
Woo! Did you like it?
ありがとう。ありがとう。ありがとうありがとう。ありがとう。
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you, thank you. Thank you.
やっぱマイク持つとね、テンション上がるね。ありがとう、ありがとう。
Holding a mic really gets the hype going. Thank you, thank you.
そしてね曲なんですけれども、なんかね、あの流行りの曲とかを調べて、ちょっと歌ってみたりとか、
And as for the songs, I looked up popular tracks and tried singing them,
あとは自分がね歌いたい曲をね、入れ込んでみました。
and also included songs I personally wanted to sing.
何曲かはね、ちょっとね、カバー動画にしたいかなと思っております。はい。
I'm thinking of making cover videos for a few of them. Yeah.
そしてね、なんと残り2曲！
And, believe it or not, only two songs left!
最後までね、盛り上がっていただければなと思います！はい。
I hope you'll keep the energy high all the way to the end!
はい、それでは聞いてください。YOASOBIさんの『アドベンチャー』！
Alright, then please listen to YOASOBI's "Adventure"!
いつもの一日から抜け出して
Let's escape from the usual day
目が覚めるような冒険の舞台へ
to the stage of an awakening adventure,
回る地球儀を目印に さあ今会いに行こう
with the spinning globe as a landmark, let's go meet now
特別な一日に
on a special day!
緑萌ゆる新しい季節に
In a season where green flourishes,
一人見つめたブルーライト
a single blue light that I gazed upon.
顔も知らない友達にも満たないクラスメイト
Classmates I don't even know well enough to call friends—
想定外の暮らし
an unexpected life,
妄想した理想と真反対に淡々と過ぎる毎日
days passing monotonously, the exact opposite of my ideal dreams.
でもやっと会えるね 想像と現実が交わって 高鳴る胸抑えられない
But we can finally meet. Imagination and reality intersect, and my beating heart can't be contained!
約束の場所は 夢見ていた場所
The promised place is the place I dreamed of.
忘れられない1日が今始まる
An unforgettable day is starting now!
待ちに待った今日は特別な日
The long-awaited today is a special day.
日常から少しはみ出して
Stepping a little outside the everyday routine,
ほらシャッターを切って写し出せば
look, if you click the shutter and capture it,
どうしたってこぼれるような笑顔ばかり
there are nothing but overflowing smiles no matter what.
誰かが言い出して飛び乗ったコースターも お揃いのカチューシャも
The roller coaster someone suggested we jump on, and the matching headbands—
かけがえのない瞬間で溢れてる 待ち時間さえも愛しく思える
overflowing with irreplaceable moments, making even the wait time feel so precious.
次はどこに行こうか 軽やかに歩く
Where should we go next? Walking light-heartedly,
不思議なほどに気が付けば過ぎている時間
time somehow passes by before you even notice.
太陽が沈んだ街を飾る 光が織りなすパレードに
The parade of lights weaving through the city at sunset
心奪われ噛み締める 本当にここにこれてよかったな
captivates my heart. I'm so glad I came here!
待ちに待った今日は特別な日
The long-awaited today is a special day.
いつも通りから飛び出して
Leaping out from the usual routine,
ほらシャッターを切っても写せない
look, even if you click the shutter, you can't capture
思い出がいつでも待っている
the memories that are always waiting.
春も夏も秋も冬も
Spring, summer, fall, winter,
この場所で見つけた笑顔が ひらひらといくつも積もっていく
the smiles we found in this place pile up gently one after another.
さあ次はいつ会いに行けるかな 当たり前から抜け出して
When can we go meet again? Breaking away from the ordinary,
限界の無い冒険の舞台へ
to the endless stage of adventure,
回る地球儀を目印に さあ今会いに行こう
with the spinning globe as a landmark, let's go meet now.
特別な一日に
On a special day!
はい！『アドベンチャー』でした！ありがとうございました！
Yes! That was "Adventure"! Thank you very much!
可愛い方でしょ、振り付け。こういう振り付け。ちょんちょん、はい。
Cute choreography, right? Steps like this. Tap tap, yeah.
これピースなosecond のも。はい、まぁそんなことはどうでもいいとして……ふふっ！
And this peace sign. Well, anyway... hehe!
エージェポップメドレーは こちらで終わりたいと思います！
That concludes the APEX Medley.
はい、そしてここからは
And from here...
えー、おなじみ
Um, our usual...
告知メドレー、え、告知メドレーだ！じゃあ告知メドレー！
Announcement Medley— ah, the Announcement Medley! Okay, Announcement Medley!
はい、おなじみのグッズの告知です。デリリリリ、ボンッ！
Yes, it's time for our familiar merchandise announcement. Deriliriliri, boom!
特典いよいよ4周年記念グッズ発売決定！
And finally, the 4th anniversary goods release is confirmed!
グッズの種類が3種類となっております。
The merchandise consists of three different items.
はい、B2タペストリー、巻物ロングTシャツ、ビビぬいぐるみキーホルダー、そして特典にポストカードがついてきます。
Yes: B2 Tapestry, Scroll Long T-Shirt, Bibi Plush Keychain, and a bonus postcard.
えー、こちらの特典ですね、数量限定で直筆サイン入りポストカードがついていきます。
These bonuses come with a quantity-limited postcard featuring an autograph.
えー、直筆のサインはね、本当に久しぶりに書くので、ぜひね、ゲットしていただきたいなと思います。
Since I haven't written autographs by hand in a really long time, I hope you'll all get one.
はい、ではね、各グッズのご紹介。
Now, let's introduce each item.
まず1つ目はB2タペストリーです。イラストは秋音さんに描いていただきました。
First up is the B2 Tapestry, illustrated by Akine-san.
昔からね、本当に大好きなイラストレーター様で、もう歌も上手いし、もうずっと尊敬する人にね、描いていただいたので本当に嬉しかったので、みんなもね、ぜひ手に入れてください。
As someone I've truly loved and deeply respected for a long time as an illustrator, I was so happy she drew this for me, so I hope everyone will get one.
そして2つ目は、巻物ロングTシャツ。
And second is the Scroll Long T-Shirt.
前にね、結構昔かな、あの、ロングTシャツをね、黒色で出したので、今回は白にしてみました。そのときにもね、好評だったので、
A while back, quite some time ago, I released a long T-shirt in black, so this time I tried white. It was well-received back then, too.
え、しかもね、トワもね、めっっちゃ使いやすいじゃんと思って購入して、もう一回ね、いいなと思ったので今回作ることにしました。
And also, I thought 'this is super easy to use!' and bought it myself, and thought it'd be great to make again.
腕の部分にはトワの名前が入っておりまして、なんと胸のところにはイラストも入っております。
The sleeves have my name on them, and the chest area features an illustration.
いや、カラーじゃなくてね、モノトーンっぽい感じにしたんですけれども、このね、理由としては普段の服にも使えそうかなって思ってこのようなデザインにしました。
Instead of full color, I went with a monotone vibe. The reason is I wanted something you could easily wear in daily life.
実際ね、トワもこういう服を使ってるんですけども、そのジャージっぽくない感じ、このカラーをやめることによってすごいジャージっぽくなくて普段使いしやすいような感じだったので、本当に自分も結構使ってるからほしいなと思って作ったっていうのもあります。
Actually, I wear clothes like this too, and by dropping the bright colors, it doesn't look like athletic wear and is easy to wear daily. Since I use stuff like this myself, part of why I made it was because I wanted one.
そしてグッズ最後、ビビぬいぐるみキーホルダー。
And the final item: the Bibi Plush Keychain.
え、以前ね、ビビのぬいぐるみを出したときに、ホロメンからもね、大好評「かわいい！」って言ってもらったりとか、ぬいぐるみ欲しいて言ってお渡しした子もいて、
When I released the Bibi plushie before, fellow holomembers praised it, saying 'So cute!' and some even asked for one when I handed them out.
自分の中でもね、「え、めちゃかわいいじゃん！」って思っていたので、そのね、あの、でっかい抱っこできるぐらいの大きさだったビビをぎゅっと小さくしてキーホルダーにしてもらえました！めっっちゃかわいいのでぜひ購入してみてください。
I thought it was super cute myself, so I had that big huggable-sized Bibi shrunk down into a keychain! It's super cute, so please check it out.
ということでグッズのご紹介でした。各グッズセットもあるし、単品販売もあるので、ぜひこのあと概要欄をチェックしてみてください。よろしくお願いします。
That concludes the merchandise introduction. There are sets and individual items available, so please check the description box afterward. Thank you!
というわけでグッズ告知でしたーー！
And that was the merchandise announcement!
はい、はい、概要欄にね、URLを載せておきますので配信後 にご購入をお願いいたします！
Yes, yes, I'll put the URL in the description box, so please purchase after the stream!
はい、そして初めて、なんとこのあとメンバーシップ限定のライブをやろうと思います！
And first— surprisingly, we'll be having a members-only live stream right after this!
打ち上げみたいな感じだね、メンバーシップのそのライブでは盛り上がる曲を歌おうかなと思っております。
It's like an afterparty vibe, where I'm planning to sing upbeat songs to hype things up.
ので、ぜひメンバーシップ登録をよろしくお願いいたします！
So please consider registering for membership!
マジでさ、みんながやっててさ、あ、いいなと思いつつもやってこなかったメンバーシップ限定ライブ、今回初めてやりますのでよろしくお願いします！
Seriously, seeing everyone else do members-only lives and thinking 'that looks nice,' yet never doing one myself... I'm doing it for the first time, so please look forward to it!
はい、そして最後、告知、まだあります！これ最後！
And finally— there's still one more announcement! This is the last one!
「なんだってーは」というコメントがいっぱい流れています。
The chat is flooded with 'What?!' comments.
ジーーーン。
*Teary-eyed*
はい。いやこれね、ちょっと分かってるかな？分かってる？あ、いや、分かってないよね？うん、分かってない、と。分か、うん、分かってないね、うん、分かってないよね、はいはい。
Yeah. Do you guys get it? Do you? Ah, wait, you don't get it, do you? Yeah, you don't get it.
はい、そうです！なんとびっくりでしょ？新曲、あります！
Yes, that's right! Surprised? There's a new song!
イェーーーイ！ライブにもね、手掛けてくださったバズジーさんにまた書き下ろししていただきましたーー！
Yay! Written once again by BuzzG-san, who also worked on my live!
はい、爽やかなね、爽やかなね、と
Yes, a refreshing— refreshing, and—
どうなってんだ？
What's going on?
爽やかなね、爽やかなロック調のね、どんだけか。え、爽やかなロック調の楽曲になっております。
A refreshing, rock-style track— how many times do I say it? It's a refreshing rock-style song.
タイトルは、STYというタイトルになっております。
The title is 'S.T.V'.
ジャケットはこんな感じ、ひゃーん。
The jacket looks like this, ta-da.
こちらもね、え、なんとグッズとして、あの、CDとしてシングルとして発売するので
This will also be released as a single CD as merchandise...
ぜひ チェックをよろしくお願いします！
Please make sure to check it out!
はい！ S.T.Yっていうのはね、なんかの略なんです。
Yes! S.T.Y is an abbreviation of something.
えー、こちらのね、何の略かと言うのは歌詞の中に答えが載ってるかも…
Um, what it stands for might be answered in the lyrics...
しれない、
...perhaps.
ていうか既に答えが載ってるかも、しれない。いやまあそんな答えいいんだけどさ
Well, or rather, the answer might already be there. Well, that answer's fine though, but...
考えながら聞いてくれれば嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you listen while thinking about it.
えーそれでは、聞いてください。S.T.Y！
Well then, please listen. S.T.Y!
そっと振り返った軌跡 どうしたって光って
The gentle footprint I looked back on shines no matter what,
ありふれた君がいつだって スーパーヒーロー
You, so ordinary, are always my superhero.
いつもポンコツだった私 飛べなくて未完成
I was always a klutz, incomplete and unable to fly.
アヒルの子はアヒルノママかもなんてさ
Wondering if an ugly duckling stays just an ugly duckling forever,
らしさなんてほっといて 君となんかちょっと似ていて
Leaving my true self behind, looking a bit like you,
デコボコだからジャストに噛み合うパズルピース
We're mismatched puzzle pieces that fit together perfectly.
繋げたい 繋ぎたい 届かない言葉も
I want to connect, I want to connect, even unreachable words.
いつかは誰かの何かに成りたいから
Because someday I want to become something to someone.
crazy No lazy 夢の中 夢を見せて
crazy No lazy, show me dreams within my dreams.
Always going 何千回 何万回 膝をついても
Always going, no matter how many thousands or tens of thousands of times I fall to my knees,
最大級 I love youで立ち上がれるから
I can stand back up with a maximum-grade I love you.
伸びきり オーバーヒート 消えそうなハッピーも勇気も振り絞っちゃって
Stretched to the limit, overheating, squeezing out my fading happiness and courage,
大失敗も後悔さえ愛せるなら 背中には君という羽
If I can embrace even major failures and regrets, I have wings called you on my back.
チックタック追い越して いつもどっか沸いた焦燥感
Overtaking tick-tock, an impatience that always boils somewhere.
隣で走る君と織り成すアレイアストーリー
An alayia story woven with you running by my side.
Non fiction
Non-fiction
君の色が私を塗り替えて
Your colors repaint me,
壊れかけの音で響くから
Resonating with a broken sound.
おとぎ話の続きをもっと描きたいんだよ
I want to draw more of the fairy tale's continuation.
Palette Palette 連れて行くよ
Palette, Palette, I'll take you with me.
きっと何千回 何万回…
Surely thousands, tens of thousands of times...
Always going 何千回 何万回 迷い込んでも
Always going, no matter how many thousands or tens of thousands of times I get lost,
最大級 I love youな君がいるから
Because you, with your maximum-grade I love you, are here.
落としずてしゃるなサンキュー それでもってラッキーも運命も手繰り寄せて
Don't drop your guard, thank you. Even so, pulling luck and fate closer,
もうバイバイの涙も忘れないよ
I won't forget the tears of saying goodbye either.
飛べなかった私のその背中には君という羽
On my back, which couldn't fly, are wings called you.
常闇トワ4周年記念ライブ スペシャルサンキュー J-Melodyいかがだったでしょうか？
How was Tokoyami Towa's 4th Anniversary Live Special Thank You J-Melody?
ライブタイトルは先ほど披露いたしました、buzzGさん作詞作曲の『S.T.Y.』とかけて決めました。
The live title was decided in connection with 'S.T.Y.', written and composed by buzzG, which I performed earlier.
いつもみんなありがとう！
Thank you everyone as always!
こちらの『S.T.Y.』と合わせてホロライブオリジナル曲『常闇トワ1st Single S.T.Y.』がCDシングルとして発売いたします！
Along with this 'S.T.Y.', the Hololive original CD single 'Tokoyami Towa 1st Single S.T.Y.' will be released!
概要欄を更新して…確認してみてください！
Please check the description box!
S.T.Y.は、今夜2024年1月4日0時にも配信されます！
"S.T.Y." will also be streaming tonight,
January 4th, 2024, at midnight!
CDシングルが届く前にぜひ聴いてみてください！
Please be sure to listen to it
before your CD single arrives!
受注生産アッドトラックはCDシングル購入者のみしか聴けないので、こちらも聴きたい方はぜひCDをご購入ください！
The made-to-order add-track is only for CD purchasers,
so please get the CD if you want to hear it!
では感想は、#常闇トワ4周年記念ライブ でたくさんつぶやいてね！
Please share your thoughts a lot with
#TokoyamiTowa4thAnnivLive!
今日は本当にありがとうございました！常闇トワでした！
Thank you all so much today!
This was Tokoyami Towa!